The who's who in the whodunnit!
Murder on the Orient Express is a drama, thriller,
mystery film directed by Sidney Lumet.
In 1935, when his train is stopped by deep snow, detective Hercule Poirot is
called on to solve a murder that occurred in his car the night before.
Hercule Poirot, played by Albert Finney.
Mrs. Harriet Belinda Hubbard, played by Lauren Bacall.
Signor Bianchi, played by Martin Balsam.
Greta Ohlson, played by Ingrid Bergman.
Colonel Arbuthnot, played by Sean Connery.
Hector MacQueen, played by Anthony Perkins.
Murder on the Orient Express is a 1974 British mystery film directed by Sidney Lumet, produced by John
Brabourne and Richard Goodwin, and based on the 1934 novel of the same name by Agatha Christie.
The film has an all-star cast, and features the Belgian detective Hercule Poirot (Albert Finney), who is asked by a railway director
(Martin Balsam) to investigate the murder of an American business tycoon (Richard Widmark) aboard the Orient Express train.
The various suspects are portrayed by Lauren Bacall, Ingrid Bergman, Sean Connery, John Gielgud, Jean-Pierre Cassel, Vanessa
Redgrave, Michael York, Rachel Roberts, Jacqueline Bisset, Anthony Perkins, Denis Quilley, Colin Blakely, and Wendy Hiller.
The screenplay is by Paul Dehn.
The film was a commercial and critical success.
Bergman won the Academy Award for Best Supporting Actress, and the film received five other nominations at the 47th Academy Awards:
Best Actor (Finney), Best Adapted Screenplay, Best Original Score, Best Cinematography, and Best Costume Design.
The film explores themes of based on novel or book,
repayment, detective, passenger, investigation.
The tone is mind_bending and emotional and thought_provoking.